A Phoenix will rise. The X-Men will fall.
Dark Phoenix is a science fiction, action,
adventure film directed by Simon Kinberg.
The X-Men face their most formidable and powerful foe when one of
their own, Jean Grey, starts to spiral out of control.
During a rescue mission in outer space, Jean is nearly killed
when she's hit by a mysterious cosmic force.
Once she returns home, this force not only makes her
infinitely more powerful, but far more unstable.
The X-Men must now band together to save her soul and battle aliens
that want to use Grey's new abilities to rule the galaxy.
Jean Grey / Dark Phoenix, played by Sophie Turner.
Charles Xavier / Professor X, played by James McAvoy.
Hank McCoy / Beast, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Scott Summers / Cyclops, played by Tye Sheridan.
Erik Lensherr / Magneto, played by Michael Fassbender.
Ororo Munroe / Storm, played by Alexandra Shipp.
Dark Phoenix (marketed internationally and released on home media as X-Men: Dark Phoenix) is a 2019
American superhero film based on Marvel Comics featuring the superhero team the X-Men.
It is a sequel to X-Men: Apocalypse (2016), the twelfth installment in the X-Men film
series, and the fourth and final installment of the prequel films.
It marks the first main X-Men film without the involvement of Hugh Jackman as Wolverine, and the last to be produced by Bad Hat Harry
Productions, though the company was uncredited due to sexual assault allegations made against Bryan Singer in 2019.
Written and directed by Simon Kinberg, it stars James McAvoy, Michael Fassbender, Jennifer Lawrence,
Nicholas Hoult, Sophie Turner, Tye Sheridan, Alexandra Shipp, and Jessica Chastain.
Dark Phoenix tells the origin story about how Jean Grey becomes the Phoenix.
The story revolves around Jean struggling with mental illness
after a cosmic force enhances her psychic powers.
It follows Jean as she tries to avoid hurting the people she loves,
while other parties seek to control or kill her.
After X-Men: Days of Future Past (2014) erased the events of X-Men: The Last Stand (2006) from the series' timeline, Kinberg expressed interest in a new adaptation of Chris Claremont and John Byrne's "The Dark Phoenix Saga" in a
future film that would be more faithful than his previous attempt with X-Men: The Last Stand, which was met with a mixed reception, with even Kinberg and co-writer Zak Penn ultimately unimpressed with the film.
The new adaptation was confirmed as a follow-up to Apocalypse in 2016.
Kinberg signed on as director in June 2017, with the majority of
the cast set to return from X-Men: Apocalypse.
Filming began later that month in Montreal and was completed in October 2017; the entire
third act was reshot in late 2018 after test screenings yielded poor responses.
The film is dedicated to the memory of X-Men co-creator
Stan Lee, who died on November 12, 2018.
Dark Phoenix was theatrically released in the United States by 20th Century
Fox on June 7, 2019, to a critical and commercial failure.
Deadline Hollywood estimated the film lost $133 million after marketing and
distribution costs, making it one of the biggest box-office bombs of all time.
The film explores themes of superhero, mutant,
telekinesis, based on comic, superhero team.
The tone is thought_provoking.